the pop under uh is is what another
great trick for scammers who are
listening yeah sorry guys we should just
we should rename this episode tricks for
scammers new new new browser tricks for
scammers best part of acing when you can
just you know critical thing
[Music]
right dude
sup hackers so zero trust world just
happened and threat Locker dropped some
pretty cool stuff my favorite of the
bunch was threat Locker Cloud control
and I'll tell you why okay so when
you're trying to hack an organization
nowadays what's kind of like the go-to
approach well for most it's going to be
set up evil engine Nick and send out a
bunch of fishing emails right that way
you don't have to worry about um
two-factor authentication or anything
like that because evil engine X is just
going to let them put in their password
their tofa and then just hand you back a
session token to interact with Microsoft
365 so threat Locker realized this was a
problem and so what they decided to do
was build Cloud control which uses the
threat Locker agent to sync into
Microsoft cloud conditional access a
list of approved IP addresses from which
a user can connect right so then an
attacker gets that token that they stole
by evil engine X they try to use it to
interact with Microsoft 365 and boom
they're burned because they're not
coming from a permitted Network and they
lose access it's pretty sick it's a
great solution to the problem so
definitely check it out threat Locker
Cloud control all right back to the
show we we haven't squatted in a long
time and and uh and we did for the first
time in a while and I just can't even
move I'm just stuck in this chair by we
are you uh lifting with Mariah or did
you go you made the gym no I'm actually
lifting with so uh okay cool so he's
he's in town right now we're going to do
an episode with him um like next week um
hopefully but yeah he's been he's been
pushing me to get back in the gym and
stay consistent with it cuz like
sometimes he has to drag me out of bed
in the morning like 6:15 I'm not wanting
to get up yeah it happens and it does
feel good it does feel good to get back
lifting heavy stuff yeah that's fair I
I've been off the train for the last
week or two so slap me back into action
nice man all right well we have quite a
list of news today let's kind of uh
let's kind of go through it um I guess
I'll take the first one this write up
really dude this write up is just like
my jam right here right now like um bus
Factor member of the ctbb community you
know a part of the bug Bounty community
in general becoming a big name um did a
great write up with xss doctor on a
series of vulnerability they found in uh
and I don't know if they named the
target I know the Target so I uh I guess
I can't say what Target is but I looked
at this um this environment pretty
extensively in the past and I was not
able to uh exploit this so uh I'm
impressed that they actually found the
the full exploitation path and um how
far deep down this Rabbit Hole did you
go oh dude I was I was I was far I was
far you know I had all but one of the
components that they had to make it work
um well actually I'm sorry two there
were two of the components that they
that they had uh that to make it work so
let me let me kind of double click into
those real quick so this is an excellent
write up on client side patch rsal which
of course if you listen to pod you've
heard you've heard me talk about I love
client H path gersal um and bus Factor
does some really great uh graphs in this
write up that show how this whole thing
works so definitely check those out if
you're a little fuzzy on how cspt works
you want to share your screen for the
viewers yeah I will go ahead and share
my screen they're more my diagrams yeah
the diagrams are great um so it starts
off with you know a client side patch
reversal and he is able to um figure out
a way to manipulate the path right
excellent that's what we want with the
client side path gersal um and the
problem is we need one of two things
really to exploit a client side patch so
maybe three let's call three things one
you need a open redirect right so if you
can get it to then send the fetch
request to your domain right then you
can respond with stuff and that that
typically has impact um two if you have
the ability to upload a a Json file or
something like that that the the code
that is doing the cspt will parse and
then do something with that's one way to
go and then the Third Way is actually
just to hit an endpoint with it if
you're dealing with like a post request
or patch request that does something
like I recently had one that just
deletes the user's account right so they
would click link and it would just
delete their whole account nice um and
the one they opted for here was number
two where they uploaded a file onto the
uh on onto the server and um that is how
far I got too Joseph that is where I
went I was literally at this exact same
point but the only only thing that I
missed here was that um you know when
you go to this this URL to download the
file right here you can see they have it
as API Marketplace files then file
number MH um it would just return a Json
blob saying here's the link to the URL
or here's the link to the file right and
it wouldn't actually return the file but
what they found was that if you add the
T redirect redirect yeah dude oh No Just
redirect is there a typo yeah there's
there's a typo in the screenshot
sorry yeah doctor is like do Ted Direct
and Buzz Factor somehow still figures it
out within the same
minute because because he yeah it
changed the T to the r okay got it
that's funny yeah yeah so so um so he
anyway he figured it out um but this
redirect true parameter was the thing
that I missed right and and essentially
what that would do was make the file
actually you know uh make the server
respond with a redirect to where the
file was stored nice um uh which is
awesome and you know they they popped it
I was a little bit little bit salty
a little salty um but then what I sort
of uh also wouldn't have probably found
or or or maybe would have had a
difficult time exploiting is this next
section dude with the cores issues um
because what happens here is okay now
they're redirecting to their file stored
in like an S3 bucket right um but now
they've got issues with uh cores because
cor wasn't returning an access control
allow origin uh star header so the the
fetch request couldn't read the Json
from that cross or cross-side origin
right um and so what they actually ended
up doing was manipulating a caching
issue on on cloudflare wow I'm sorry
cloudfront um that would allow them to
get the access control all origin star
header cached in the response and uh and
then triggered the full flow reading the
JS file and then uh causing the xss so
that's insane pretty beautiful exploit
chain here from buz factor and Xs doctor
um and then they proceeded of to explain
how they fully exploited it well that
last Gadget just to just to be clear for
our listeners who are trying to exploit
something similar is is this a misc
config in the cloudfront that the
customer set
up you know that's a good question man
to be honest I I think I mean it has to
be right uh because otherwise if it was
cashing it that way then
you it would be causing problems anytime
you tried to access it but I guess the
signatures would be different so it says
it says right here when we click it the
request doesn't include An Origin header
so maybe that's the
fix it says this causes cloudfront to
cach the response yeah yeah yeah so so
so what it says to solve this we needed
to avoid clicking the download button
and instead CS let the CSP execute
naturally which would add the origin
header automatically when this happened
Cloud Player would respond with a Access
Control allow origin header okay so
because they did a top so I got it so
what they were doing before is they
would upload the file and they'd click
the file you know the button to like
grab the file link or whatever and that
would open it up as a top level
navigation in their browser which would
cach uh not having the origin header in
place right but instead of doing that
they fed it directly into the cspt and
the cspt would set the origin header
that it was sending from you know
whatever site and then uh then it would
work seemlessly that makes sense that's
beautiful man yeah beautiful bug yeah
really cool I love xss doctor everywhere
these days yeah dude he's he's popping a
lot of stuff um yeah and then you know
the the rest of this article you know I
we won't dive into it too in depth but
um they talk about how to exploit this
by using um scoped self xss so they set
a cookie to make sure that they are
logged in for this file you know
accessing this file um just for their
account on that endpoint um which is
something we talk about with maton we've
talked about plenty of times on the
podcast if you don't fully get it this
is a good article for you to fully get
it um but this technique is absolutely
essential to exploiting self xss in
modern uh environments so um good to see
someone taking it using it and Landing I
think a 22k bounty for this one that's
awesome so this is all one finding or
was there multiple iner yeah this is all
one finding and is uh and look look at
this dude we even get a little we even
get a little shout out here at the end
that's exactly right so yeah also it
says awarded 7500 at the
bottom uh yeah I guess it says 7500 but
then uh while oh okay this approach
worked on another Target in the same Pro
program earning me and my collab 2,000
this target was much better protected
okay got
it so this one's
7500 yeah yeah I will say most of my
news is AI related but we'll start with
one that is not I'm sure I'm sure you
saw this and everyone else did because
it kind of blew up on X but travle
security uh you used their you know
their very famous uh secret scanner to
scan all of common crawl so if you're
not familiar with what common crawl is
it's a massive download of basically the
entire internet and it's sort of cleaned
up but it's not really and it includ it
includes like um like it's in like this
kind of interesting it actually has like
the raw request and response um so it
includes like it's it's deeper than
actually I want to go through common
craw and look for stuff but it's huge I
think it's it's like 400 terabytes yeah
400 terab oh my gosh I'm sure someone
has an index of it out there that's like
easier to look through on like elastic
or Cabana or something but basically
this is like the the main training set
for a lot a lot of AI models because it
has so much internet data on it and they
do they do a lot of cleaning it up
cleaning it up and removing special
characters and I'm sure they drop out
HTML tags and all kinds of stuff like
they do a lot of really unique things um
the kind of nuance here with this post
is when they tweeted it they basically
said in deep seeks training data I think
they were doing that just to like get it
click B and kind of go to go a little
bit of
because common craw is used for many
more things than just deep seek like
every everyy uses it as a base and a
little bit of their findings kind of
imply that this is like dangerous
because you can tease out these secrets
that they found from the training data
and you you can't do that with current
models unless it's like really overfit
and what overfit means is just that when
you're talking to the model it'll output
the training data it'll just spit out
the training dat yeah and like no models
really do that today unless I guess it's
possible that comic craw is used so
frequently that there are some companies
that are really poorly training their
models and then releasing them open
source because there's like there's tens
of thousands of maybe hundreds of
thousands of models now on hugging face
anyways all that to say I thought that
the idea of going through comic call for
Secrets was genius maybe people didn't
do this because it was like um because
it was so much data to go through but
they found like 12,000 live API keys and
passwords and I'm sure a lot of those
were for bug bount targets yeah man I
mean definitely if I was a an attacker
this would be easy mode you know like if
you were a malicious actor that that
would be like okay just grab the whole
internet and just GP the whole internet
like it wouldn't surprise me if nation
states have already done that comic has
been out there and accessible for a ton
of people for a long time 100% being
able to just write a singular regular
expression you know I think they were
struggling with the scale as well and
they're they're like the Forefront
people in in secret scanning but they
were probably scanning for a lot of
different Secrets like if you were a
nation state actor looking for a
specific type of API key for a specific
service you could just gra for that one
thing and it would probably be pretty
easy and obviously you know nation
states have the um computing power to to
pull something like this off I just
thought it was a really genius idea and
a really cool post we'll put the link in
the in the um show notes yeah dude yeah
I mean to be honest common crawl we've
been using common craw um you know for a
while as like just I think it hooks into
Gaal GA uses common crawl and uh I think
way more does too if I'm not mistaken um
you know so we we use it for like uh
path enumeration and that sort of thing
um but yeah I hadn't really thought of
like doing the widescale security
research um for that
uh with with with regards to you know
scanning for for secrets and stuff like
that also I'm really glad that I didn't
have to set up the modules for verifying
if those keys are working it feels like
verifying if a bunch of keys that you're
that you're pulling are working for
hundreds of different Services is like a
pretty big project but it's also really
cool to have going forward like if you
could just drop a key in there and it
would just check it for all the services
and do whatever the off checks are there
to verify them is a really cool piece of
technology to have that it sounds like
they now have it's like key hacks but
like automated yeah but automated
exactly yeah I a little bit of a tangent
but I was hacking on Google earlier this
week and and so and I my buddy were
looking at um Google's Chrome web store
and I had this crazy idea for um
security research and and like I kind of
went down the path for it and and it
kind of dead ended a little bit because
of the way that it that it um is
implemented but uh all of the
organizations within or all of the like
extensions in the Chrome web store if
you're not a single developer so if it's
not tied to a single um uh Google
account right like and imagine if
grammarly or something like that was
tied to a single Google account right um
it's tied to a Google group and so you
actually go into groups. google.com and
you create a Google group and then you
like sort of slurp that Google group
into Chrome web store as like an owner
yeah that Google group owns the the
extension right so and here's the thing
in the ation like 15 times they say do
not leave this Google group open right
do not do not leave it open don't do it
you know like yeah and I was like
there's some that are definitely open
yeah and so I was like oh my gosh I got
to go and uh and like check and see if
there's any way for me to find the
Google group associated with a given
extension yes and I was like surely this
is possible it feels totally possible
dude I know and I I spent so much time
looking through the Chrome web store and
like maybe it gets put inside the CRX
files
if if could a CHR extension identify
what Google group is associated with it
then you can check the permissions on
that Google group and some of these
Google Groups are just anyone can join
yeah we need we need a channel on the
Discord that's called like close the
loop because we say this all the time
it's like if you if you use what we said
here for this thing come back and close
the loop on it and I want to have a
close the loop section on episodes where
if anybody found something that we
mentioned we close a loop on it and so
if someone does this please go close the
loop oh oh speaking of that let me dude
I don't even know if I put it in the
notes Ben I'm sorry our news section is
going to be super long it's gonna be
long today yeah so here here's what
we'll do y'all we'll just you know if
you're interested in the actual topic of
this episode which was um single page
application hacking just jump to the
time stamp because this is going to take
a second okay um somebody messaged me
and said what is it called hack advisor.
that's what it's called um because we
talked about essentially providing for
bug Bounty platforms right and we said
hey we don't want to do that that's
going to be tricky you know like
managing all the data private programs
blah blah um and somebody beside us did
it so I'm like great you know like I
don't have to do that [__] that's
wonderful um and it's hack advisor. um
so yeah I mean I don't know how it's
going to go they have uh they have
integrity yes we hack standoff 365 which
is the first time I've heard of that uh
bug crowd in hacker one on there as
platforms and they've got like looks
like quite a decent amount of um of
actual it's not it's not overly
intuitive so if you scroll down on the
main page I thought they would like have
it all sorted you have to scroll down to
see the platforms and then in each table
is the program yeah yeah so so the the
UI could definitely use some work but
you click on each individual program
it's a pretty UI though I like that yeah
yeah the UI looks great it's just not
super intuitive and then it says you
know you you can leave feedback if
you've logged in they load in some of
the medic data about the program um but
yeah I mean to be honest something the
community really needed so um yeah I'm
glad somebody did it so there's ratings
it looks
like yeah ratings so if you click into
one let me see what the rating looks
like oh yeah so no no no comments I
wonder how you the rating is like
between one to 10 so right now graffo
Labs is the top one on Integrity no it's
not well if you click more oh maybe okay
I got
you it goes beyond 10 you're saying yeah
yeah it's like an ordered so it's like
the best program on that platform that's
cool exactly so according to this right
now integrity's best uh program is uh
graphon Labs it shows hacker One's best
program is
AT&T yeah I don't know about that I
think it needs data well okay sorry the
Bounty average here is $350 on AT&T so
it shouldn't be rated number one but I
think it might be ranking it by reports
or reports times Rewards or something um
yeah but it's cool that they have like
uh it looks like green and red bubbles
like you're going to be able to up vote
and down vote yeah it's kind of like
Rate My Professor but for a program did
you ever use Rate My Professor in
college I did yeah I mean it was so
helpful to know who you because like
whenever you're trying to make a um when
you're trying to make your schedule for
the next year knowing which which one's
good and which one's bad is huge oh my
gosh yeah and you know what's crazy too
is like my schedule was kind of tight in
college so I had to like um sometimes I
had to take a professor that wasn't
great and you get into that class and
it's like totally accurate right it's
like a this right this guy sucks you
know so it's hopefully this will turn
into that for
programs uh okay cool so I I set up an
account I'm just going to see if I can
now up vote all right well let me and
I'm gonna go ahead and go ahead and add
this uh to the links for the episode
Richard I'm gonna put it under news I
love how we just do we news this news
Discovery yeah logistic stuff in the in
the middle of the podcast um all right
let me know how you go let me let me
cover this next one really Qui oh this
is cool before you can actually the
feedback you have to verify you have to
you have to log into your profile and
complete the verification process for
your um for like your what's it called
your platform account yeah your platform
account ah dude that's exactly what we
wanted to do what what what's the what's
the process like do you have to put like
a hash in your bio or something to
verify the profile and gain ability
click the ad button and select what you
were listed yeah let's see what happens
uh Integrity reso maybe maybe it might
just trust you anyways you you take a
second figure that out and then come
back and deliver it to the people let me
tell them about this next thing really
quick okay um not a big not not a big
thing it's not going to take very long
um there was a tweet uh from somebody I
follow uh Yos Zan um and it was in
Japanese uh but the Tweet was a PC for
cve 20252
2475 um I'm sorry uh
24752 um and it that was a uh an xss
uh as on the admin of a WordPress site
for a plugin that has 2 million installs
wow um and I think this kind of just
slid under the the Recon radar so um
here's a little freebie for those of you
guys that do Recon um fingerprint this
[__] and and you know at least try to
submit it to bug Bounty I know that
sometimes it's a little bit difficult to
get um admin facing xss in in WordPress
um accepted but this one has 2 million
installs so I imagine there'd be quite a
few and uh I definitely think that they
could walk away with some bounties if
they if they went ahead and sprayed this
so um give it a shot let me know how it
goes uh and and this is a little tidbit
for the the listeners that do it early
enough and listen to critical thinking
podcast as soon as it comes out and then
take action right away yeah so okay what
you findo well I'm actually well sorry
I've got two things and neither one of
these are on the news the first the
first on our news list the first one is
uh they manually review it it looks like
when I submitted my user name it said
like it says we'll review this so I kind
of like that at first you know
integration with the platform can come
later let them manually review stuff um
and then the second thing is I'm
circling back to your Chrome extension
thing really quickly so I'm sure you
noticed this if you didn't listeners I'm
sure have noticed my ublock origin got
removed um and that is one of like uh
let me actually look up how many
extensions it is I think hundreds of
thousands of extensions yeah did not
update their manifest file and um so
they're
getting um yep sorry 8454 Chrome
extensions are disabled in the next few
months wow that was posted in August of
last year they just got disabled what
this means is there is a huge market for
Builders like if you had an extension
that you Lov that went away go use AI to
rebuild it and just put it on the store
and you can you can easily make some
money you can it could easily blow up
you could do that for hacker
specifically like I don't know if like
the thing is Chrome extensions are kind
of hard to monetize man like they are a
little bit difficult I mean grammarly
does this successfully so there's a nice
you know use case for you but from what
I've seen they're pretty hard to
monetize per install and they're like
pretty cheap to buy yeah that's what I
was going to say I feel like I've seen
people exit for 50 or 100K on Chrome
extensions though which I mean if you
can get one going and just drop it off
kind of neat um but I did want to
mention that because it's kind of cool
it probably affects all of our listeners
because we all have a bunch of Chrome
extensions we use if anyone has like a
really recommended UB block origin
alternative it's there's probably just a
way to reinstall it if I wanted to but
yeah I just force reinstalled all the
ones I said no just ignore the Manifest
V3 just install again dude manifest V3
is such a [__] show too like I've been
creating a extension recently and it
doesn't allow you to like mess with grab
the data from the response of an HTP
request and I'm like what like that's so
pivotal you know to to doing an
extension so what I ended up having to
do and you have this extension I don't
know if you've installed it yet but um
what it what it's supposed to do or what
I had to do was hook into Dev tools with
the extension because there's like a um
debugger um permission that you can give
the extension and then it can hook into
Dev tools protocol you're know you're
tell you're telling all of the scammers
and uh malicious malicious uh Chrome
extension developers who listen to our
podcast how to R give the functionality
back they want no but but the thing is
with that is like the functionality is
there but what happens then is whenever
it attaches the debugger to any tab it
pops up a like a little bar underneath
your bookmark part is this plugin is
debugging your [__] that's that's like
you know so it it is very like you know
in face about it um yeah but then what
what I don't want that and I use this
thing all the time so what did I do I
disable it at the flags level right and
so now I just thinking like wow they
just really shot themselves in the foot
here with this because now I've just
disabled Chrome extensions hooking into
my you know my tabs via debugger because
I don't want to be bothered by this
little bar every time right so I don't
know man maybe it's a good security
posture decision for Chrome in general
but it's it's a pain in my ass as a
hacker yeah yeah um sweet which is
probably what they want exactly exactly
exactly uh was that that wasn't on your
list right that was just your uh your
that was just me Ranon we're we're just
doing our thing today man okay sweet um
I think it's my turn no yeah it is yeah
you talk about hack advisor so um this
is just even gonna be even quicker I I
hope and think I know a lot of our
listeners like take really great notes
um I saw that and I also know that a lot
of our hackers are sometimes wanting to
ask questions about code bases that are
longer like larger than two million
tokens and you know like cursor and wind
surf like have ways to do that I've
heard wind surf is quite good about it
um I've never really used cursor to chat
with um code bases I thought that was a
good idea though could you imagine like
let's say you're hacking open source
project like you're doing code review on
GitHub for a program if you clone it and
then open cursor and then ask questions
about the codebase about things that
might be insecure it might actually flag
things for you that are pretty cool
because it's good at codebase search but
anyways the um the thing that I want to
actually bring up is that um notebook LM
is still underrated I know people we've
mentioned it or people have probably
seen notbook LM for like the podcasting
stuff you can do where you can make a
podcast and it sounds very natural oh
yeah I love that but like the whole
purpose of notebook LM the way it was
originally designed was basically you
put a bunch of notes in there and then
you can chat with your notes and so you
can do that with entire code bases you
can do that with all of your bug Bounty
notes and it like will contextually pull
in the right data and Google Deep Mind
is really good at what they're building
so I would imagine it's quite good I
don't have like significantly strong
notes I was also thinking about what
would you think about basically using in
kaido or burp like exporting a bunch of
requests and then throwing it in there
and then just seeing if you could ask it
about the request it'd be kind of neat
that that would be pretty neat to yeah
should do I know that recently there's a
hacker that I really respect definitely
like top three hacker that I know as far
as source code review um goes and they
recently said that a little bit uh you
know thinking that that Claude 3.7 is is
going to like really be a lot you know
like um and so I think that that is
pretty sick um and that hackers really
need to be leaning into using llm stuff
which is also just one of the reasons
I'm so grateful that that you decided to
come onto the the pot as a as a co-host
because I think you do have a lot of um
that AI angle that's really necessary to
the growth of our industry um and I'm
definitely I like within the past week
or two I've become a little bit more
convinced that I need to be leaning into
this a little bit more than I am um
because there is I mean the game is
about to change for sure yeah I think so
and you know my advice to your buddy
would be like if 37 is gonna eat
everything like you be you be the person
that's holding 37 as it eats all the
bounties like you be the the hand that
it's feeding right like I mean yeah lean
into it and use that I'm sure that you
know eventually some tools will come out
that company or that companies will
especially Enterprises will deploy that
will find vulnerabilities on the way out
the door via code review but in the
short term it's like for all of the code
review bugm programs like use 37 to go
through that code and find
vulnerabilities for you right yeah
grafana I mean according to hack adviser
graan is a top program and they are open
source so you can go and GP that whole
thing um dude I will say though that
I've been like pretty Blown Away with
cursor's um ability to consume code
recently and give like a contextual
thing like I don't know what they did
with between the past couple updates but
I'll ask it about something and it'll be
like okay first I need to like identify
how this piece of code works and then I
need to like GP for this and I see all
the uses of XYZ here and then and like
and then it just very systematically
goes through the whole code base and and
can apply mass changes um you know very
consistently across the whole codebase
so um yeah very impressed yeah so that
was like my next thing so I can just
roll into it real quick and then we can
go back to yeah was basically the fact
that within the last few weeks we
haven't had a lot of time to do news
grock 3 has come out Sonic 37 has come
out and GPT 45 has come out
and with all the AI people that I follow
like there are people using each of
those in unique and cool ways that are
totally state-ofthe-art like I've been
using grock 3 it's definitely the
smartest at like like I was asking about
the content for this week show notes and
it's like yeah like you know make sure
you're using link finder and like uh
like stuff like like it's like
referencing and it was it was saying
like you know make sure you use mat
Place rules in burps uh match and replay
section and other models didn't get like
uh in the weeds or as Technical and you
know I'm holding that master class on
Tuesday where I'm talking about how to
hack AI agents when I put the context of
my of my um huge blog post like you know
5,500 words in there about AI security I
did that for all the top models because
I just wanted advice for like hey what
am I missing here what what things have
I not talked about what examples did I
not have what scenarios was I not
thinking about none of them gave me
anything useful besides grock 3 and it
gave me two things that I added
immediately so I think that grock 3 even
though it doesn't do well with long
context it's not going to do well if you
incorporate a cursor in my opinion CU
it's not as like excellent on tool
calling but I think that it has a deeper
technical understanding of appsec and AI
security than any other model so if
you're interesting yeah and it's free if
you have like a premium thing to use I
think you get limited per day but like
some of the other ones are like 20 bucks
a month or 40 or whatever and I think
grock Super is 40 but if you just have
like the $8 a month you know Twitter
premium or X premium you can still use
it a bunch in the UI and that's what
I've been using and it you know I
haven't ran out of requests wow that's
pretty sick dude yeah I I heard grock 3
was is doing really well um and what
surprises me and I've I heard a ruckus
about Sonic 3.7 as well but I haven't
heard much about GPT
4.5 well let me tell you real quick one
to Circle back what you said about 37
it's definitely the best at coding and
now cursor defaults to that agent mode
that's why you're able to see that stuff
it's doing and then it does more pulling
of like exam it does more pulling of
code that's not full files you probably
saw that like when it searches for um
like a function name and it goes and
looks it up then it'll say like oh
getting file or lines like 100 to 150
like around that function name so that's
probably what you saw and Sonet 37 is
fantastic much better at coding it you
know beat the scores from software
engineering benchmarks as far as 45
initially when it launched it did not
have great benchmarks but everyone who
used it said it had like the big model
smell more than any other model and so
like it it's much more humanlike when
you interact with it it's not as prone
to give you like these gigantic pair
like Wikipedia articles for your
questions it's going to give you a much
more contextualized shorter smaller
better answer
um and I have heard from some people
that even though it's not as good at
coding as like Sonic 37 if you're trying
to oneshot like an entire application
that it can sometimes solve one shot
requests for like a big app complex app
that Gro or 37 failed to do so I think
it's basically on par with them maybe
not as good as 37 if you're like having
it interact with your entire code base
like I think clearly 37 is the best
thing in in cursor and in Wind Surf and
all of these things but I think as far
as like if you just have like one big
app and you just wanted to generate your
initial POC 4 five might be the thing to
go to um so yeah interesting that yeah
and I think that's often what we do as
hackers is you know there are some some
uh you know some moments where we are
trying to just write a whole application
but most of the time we're just writing
a little PC script and you're just like
just write this thing that does this
thing just like this it can be it can be
a little slower than the other so that
might be frustrating for that but if you
have the time to wait for it yeah it and
the denials are are kind of a pain too
um so I I would like to see you know
less of those moving forward and I know
that's going to be a pain for some of
the the stuff that we're trying to
integrate into um to Kao uh to shift um
in this upcoming section so uh
development cycle so I I think that'll
be that'll be a challenge moving forward
for security researchers grock will deny
nothing so oh really Gro is basically
jailbroken yeah that's awesome dude yeah
I have seen that it's pretty unhinged is
yeah there's like an NSFW like voice
mode and stuff on the app it's like it's
kind of
that's hilarious um all right so moving
into the next one there was a write up
um by jorian another valued member of
the ctbb community um and this one was
sort of building upon the work that we
covered um I guess when this launches
probably two weeks back yeah uh with uh
paulos uh on the double click hijacking
and some of the pop stuff that he's done
yeah um and and so the I read through
this article and there's some very very
interesting things in here with
hijacking um essentially using another
frame in hijacking the um details about
how our Clicks in our in our spacing or
hitting our space bar Works uh very
interesting stuff but the the two main
takeaways that I'd like to distill it
down to uh for you guys for me were were
these two sections right here um the pop
under uh is is what another great trick
for scammers who are listening yeah
sorry guys I'm we should just we should
rename this episode tricks for scammers
new new new browser tricks for
scammers new browser tricks for
scammers you'll probably do the rounds
on YouTube we oh my gosh dude that's
hilarious um well you know I got now I
got to deliver so here's how you do the
pop under guys one of the things that
that's been tricky you know with with
window. focus and and I love that
somebody else said this because this has
been this sums up my experience with
window. Focus completely quote there is
the intuitive window. Focus method that
should allow you to focus any window
reference in reality this method very
rarely works and you should not
definitely not rely on it from my
experience I I totally agree it's just
very weird how that that I don't know
why that just so rarely works yeah um
but he said there's another more obscure
way of focusing a window and that's
using the target argument of window.
open and I use the target argument of
window. open all the time and for some
reason I never considered this as a
possibility for um for focusing Windows
as well um so definitely a uh a cool
approach here is that you can perform a
window. open um and set the just the
hash on that page uh and it will not
reload the page but it will focus that
window if you provide the the um the
correct Target uh which is the name of
that window um and it's in the shared
browsing context so that will be really
helpful for for causing um is that
something that they could remove for
security purposes down the line not
really there's too much there's too much
like um
Legacy you know there's there's going to
be too much stuff that's depending on
that functionality to work so I I think
that's one really cool takeway is is
using that for a pop under which can be
really helpful for these sort of attacks
um and then did did that remind you of
anything that you could have potentially
exploit in the past that you weren't
able to yeah you
know it's a useful piece of
functionality for crafting some you know
really obscure out their exploits but to
be honest if my exploits are getting to
the point where I'm needing like a pop
under and stuff I start to question
like is this exactly what I should be
doing with my hacking time I'm I'm not
sure um so it it's cool it's something
to have in your pocket you know there's
this there's a scenario in which um you
know it could be helpful for an exploit
uh especially if you're in a live
hacking event or something and you just
really want to make something work uh
but you know it's probably not gonna
land you a crit sure cool so all right
and then this other one was this this
other one was this right here which is
um using the window. move to function
I'm a big fan of like knowing what
functions you can call on a cross origin
uh window and there is this move to
method that you can call on a pop-up
window and that will move the the um the
window to a specific spot and I've seen
people do really funny stuff with this
sometimes like you'll try to go close a
tab and it'll like move out of the way I
hate that so much and stuff like that so
there's some weird stuff you can do with
that um that's the scammer trick number
three yeah there there you go guys um
but all of these can be useful you know
and in this scenario he he just provides
an improvement to the double click
jacking um techniques where you know you
needed to align the button with the you
know button on the on the window that
you're trying to click Jack on um and
this move to functionality makes it much
more simple yep sweet dude yep all right
so that's that one let's see where where
are we at um okay I'm sorry let me just
let me take the next one um this one is
going to be real quick but it's in the
same vein since we're talking about uh
Pop lunders um there was a tweet uh that
was responding to the article that we
just covered um by renoa and he drops a
PC right here I'm just going to show it
on my screen he said I reported this
this to Chrome but they're not going to
patch it and so he drops like this PC
and it's so interesting let me see um
let me see if I can actually get it to
get it to share what that the PC
actually does but essentially the tldr
of it is you you click on the screen and
it pops up a new window I'm not sure
it's going to show in my in my um in my
environment no it's not the pop-up
didn't show yeah the pop-up didn't show
but it pops up a window and then it
triggers like this sign in with Google o
which has some connection to Chrome and
it will pop up this this little side
panel which you also can't see on my
screen share so sorry about that but it
it pops up another little uh screen at
the top right that says sign in with
Google you know and it's like a part of
chrome um but when that piece pops up it
triggers a Dom event on on on the the
page and it moves that window that you
just opened back and BR brings your
window forward so it's effectively a pop
under you can pop up a window and then
move it under your current window by by
utilizing this um this focusing
mechanism that comes along with the
signin with chrome um functionality so
sorry I started laughing so hard when
you started saying that it just feels
like the same exact vein so it it is
dude I mean it I mean there's lots of
ways to accomplish it um but this one I
think is particularly creative itz
Chrome's own um you
know their own sign with with Google
features to to cause the pop under yeah
very cool um I don't know how much of
this we want to keep going through or if
we want to
Pivot um well tell you what let let me
at least cover this last thing just real
quick the very last link here in our
notes and I'll share my screen to show
everyone is a person named Devon or
Devan their um their hacker hand looks
like it's called it's asadas and Le
speak um let me share
share screen here we go um also the
name's great right like I love the
everything I learned or everything I'll
forget type uh post but they they
tweeted this everything I learned about
prompt injection attacks in the last two
years in this guide this should be your
stepping stone into the team of into the
field of AI red teaming um so I'm going
to switch to that tab basically it is an
extremely comprehensive guide for a
bunch of ways to do prompt injection and
jaw breaking like extremely
comprehensive I actually it's so
comprehensive that I was scared I would
lose it and so I just saved it off to a
different place in case they take it
down because I want access to this and I
think it is similar to my um mega post I
just released on how to hack agents this
is something I think you can copy and
paste into a model and as long as it
doesn't get derailed by all the prompt
injection payloads in here it would be
extremely beneficial for generating more
prompt injection payloads or more
jailbreaking payloads um yeah I was just
really excited to see this so be the
show notes this this is like a source
for um what you would feed into AI to
generate AI jailbreaking well I'm saying
you could do it for that in general this
should just be a reference for when
you're looking at jailbreaking and
prompt injecting it's like similar to my
mega post I think you want to look in
here for both ideas and for payloads
that you can copy and paste and then
just adapt to your usage dude I don't
know man I just don't love jailbreaking
models dude it's just so like annoyingly
non-deterministic okay well I'm gonna
have to jump my other news note then
because I think you're gonna love this
oh my God okay fine PX as a part of his
attacking AI course he just did yeah
built a tool that allows you to just
give it the thing you're trying to do
like ATT tactic a technique and and and
then a bunch of ausc things and it just
generates all the payloads for you wow
and then and then you just need to try
them over and over until you get the
result yeah yeah I assume you just use
them in automate or in ffuf or whatever
and just get the outcome you want um but
you know like you could imagine that
like you want to do data exfiltration by
image markdown rendering with every
officiation technique then you would
just generate all those payloads like
you would choose you know U chat history
or system prompt extration then you
would choose you know image markdown
rendering then you would choose select
all then you click download and then all
of a sudden it gives you a text file or
whatever of all of the payloads to do
that I hope that there's a feature where
you can give it an
abstract goal and then it uses an llm to
generate the payloads for you on the
back end I think that that would
probably be a product he could even sell
um so anyways yeah free shot out there
very interesting yeah with you it's
tough like the non-determinism makes it
like less fun to hack than just like
traditional vulnerabilities yeah and I
don't know I guess I'm just so used to
that moment where I'm like yes I
exploited it you know and then like and
then I when with when I'm jailbreaking
something I like press enter again and
it's like no and I'm like [__] you know
like it's so frustrating yeah I was
speaking I was speaking to all of hacker
in Dallas um uh this last week and um
schoy mentioned that same frustration
and how that that affects him whenever
he's hacking and I think that um you
know one thing that I brought up that
was really interesting is it can
determine um it can be kind of affected
by whether the models quantized in that
moment and another really frustrating
thing is that a lot of times these um
apps on hacker one I you've probably
hacked on some of them like the AI
challenges will have like built-in
history and no way to clear that history
so once they're in like this mode of
rejecting you then they just keep
rejecting you and so it's really
frustrating as a tester um because you
don't know what to do right it's like do
I just send a million messages to kind
of clear that out of the context or
whatever and so yeah you're right it can
be really frustrating to hack these
applications and if there's program
managers listening like that's like
really good advice like that you should
set up some mechanism by which because a
lot of these are like Alpha features
right because companies want them tested
before they like put them all the way to
prod um you still want to give away to
kind of reset the the context or the
chat history in such a way that attack
can be fresh yeah absolutely I think
good insight's there um moving to the
last news topic we do have to cover
Shadow repeater uh I think that is a
really cool project that burp released
um and I'm looking you know I looked at
the the video that Gareth posted and I
love the concept of having sort of like
in AI watch your your your testing
technique and then try to implement it
it you know itself um and I wanted to
get your thoughts on
how how that feels to you the repeater
yeah Shadow repeater oh um so I mean in
general like my very first thoughts were
this is exactly what I talked about on
the Pod like three weeks ago you know
like we said that this would be like
really cool to say you know to like
rightclick or click somewhere in shift
and basically be able to send a diff of
all the things you've been trying and
all the responses you've been trying and
then output um you know the next few
payloads or let it continue to hack on
your behalf um yeah that's my honest
thoughts I think what you you were just
implying that um having it happen
automatically is kind
of interesting you know so I I I thought
about that you know when we first
discussed this I my first thought was
like I don't love that it is
automatically trying stuff without me
giving it a goal right and like that
just feels a little bit like you know it
might get a little carried away and be
like oh okay you know now I've got sqli
let's drop drop the database you know
like you know like no you know um and
hopefully that Port sger has put in some
some smart guard rails there you know
saying hey let's just make sure we're
doing non-destructive testing in any way
you know that sort of thing um but then
you know
the my my honest thoughts on it is I
think it's super cool I think it's
awesome that it exists and uh I think
that I would be more comfortable using
AI when I give it a direct goal and it
is very goal oriented on that rather
than it looks at my my actions tries to
extract a goal and then and then
implements it right because it could
misinterpret what I want yeah I think
they have a model where you pay for
token usage too so it would be maybe a
little bit annoying to like always
toggle it on and off because like we're
sometimes testing on repeater and we
would not want Shadow repeater to like
go spin my tokens you know what I mean
yeah and so then and then sometimes you
would want it to do it like you said so
I think maybe like a manual kickoff
would be better but dude how sick would
it be if you're like testing something
and then all of a sudden shadow repter
like yo sup figured it out here's here's
the crit I figured it out for you yeah
it be so sick D that would be so sick so
I love the vision I love where it's
going um you know here here's a here's
something that that I think could maybe
even make it awesome would be just like
let me um Let me give it some some guard
rails or or maybe give it uh some limit
of requests that's the other thing is
like maybe I don't want you to spend you
know 200 requests brute forcing through
all of the asky characters one by one
you know like that seems like it's going
to consume a lot of tokens it's going to
consume a lot of bandwidth a lot of time
um if I could just provide some extra
insight into it like maybe there's just
a box next to each request and it
doesn't start hacking on stuff until I
say hey I'm trying to figure out xss
here or something like that then it kind
of takes that my testing methodology the
clippy
methodology you might be trying to
exploit PSAL here would you like me to
do it that's a great idea I love that it
really is yeah cuz then it's like
guessing what you're trying to do too
which is kind of neat yeah and do you do
you want help with that or like am I
right yes or no you know like that sort
of thing that would be really helpful
also this is just like something that
maybe everyone should be aware of with
both shift and burp AI like your
requests are being sent to a third party
two third parties right it's like it's
going to pors wiger or to us and then
also to the model provider and also back
right it's like I don't think there's an
issue there I don't really like I trust
like we use mostly gemini or sonic I
trust anthropic and Google on our side I
don't know what burp is using but I also
trust me we're not going to do anything
with anyone's data but it's just like
you should definitely be aware of this
like if you're hacking a government
agency or you've signed like a super
strict NDA should probably be careful
where you submit that so yeah yeah for
sure but yeah overall I'm excited to see
AI features getting integrated more into
the proxies I'm excited to continue
deving on shift I think uh this next
iteration what we've got coming up is
going to be sick um and we definitely
are going to have base improvements to
the product as well um just the core
functionality of it so thanks for all
the uh the listeners out there that are
supporting that product and
yeah it's definitely basically
supporting an alpha or beta product and
we're very appreciative so yeah
definitely appreciate that um all right
so I think that's the end of the news
section 45 minutes in uh let's move to
attacking Spas uh so the thought here
was that a while back um I want to say
it was like episode 30 something maybe
39 uh Joel and I did an episode on like
various application architectures and I
was going to sort of make that this
episode a followup to that one but I
decided to f more on single page
applications because almost everything
we see nowadays is a single page
application um and I just want to make
sure that we're sort of comparing notes
with listeners on what the sort of best
practices are for going after single
page applications um and you know what
kind of stuff is not actually going to
help very much um so okay uh when I see
a single page application first thing
this sort of comes to mind is I have
everything that I need right like
everything you
actually nowadays inversely when I go up
against something that's not a single
page application I'm like [__] like
there is some Javascript file that's
some on some like weird page deep in
this thing that I'm not seeing right and
I'm worried about that you know um but
with the single page application you've
got everything in the files um you may
have to web uh you know unwe pack it and
and get all the data out but it's such a
great place to start having all of the
JS files for the whole application in
one spot yeah yeah absolutely I think um
for me it almost always screams and
we'll talk about this a little bit later
but it just always screams like the
ability to view all the features and
know all the end points which is like
you said very beneficial and makes it
much more fun to hack I think yeah
that's a great point the features is is
a is a big thing right because we'
talked about in the past like how
feature Flags get integrated into these
environments too with with a with a
single page application those are much
more likely to be just like a JavaScript
blob you know on the front end you can
just say turn on Advanced feature you
know true or yeah I'm in this AB test
group you know that sort of thing um and
and I think that's a part of the initial
Recon and Recon sort of has a has the
term Recon sort of makes you think about
like asset enumeration that sort of
thing I really think about Recon as well
in this sort of more application Recon
sense where you're you're going through
you're downloading all the JS files
you're beautifying all the JS files
you're you're ging for endpoints you're
identifying feature flag you can turn on
and turn off doing that Recon pays
massive dividends is a and is a much
more relevant skill to hackers that are
are in the weeds hacking on an
application than uh you know running
subdomain enumeration or something like
that and trying to find some some asset
if you're trying to go for core impact
on the main application yeah yeah um so
all right let's see let's see what else
we got on the list here um yeah I mean
you you mentioned it there I want to
whenever Justin says like turn on
feature Flags what he means is either
something in local storage or something
that's like a client side matro place
you know it's very frequently a client
side matro place which is really great
almost all these single page apps just
is like very technical or very practical
way to look at this for any testers who
aren't super familiar with it almost all
single page apps will have like a
slashme or a slash config or a slash
features like request that happens when
you load the page like with single page
apps I find myself doing like a command
shift R kind of frequently because I
want to see those requests right I want
to see what are those initial requests
it makes and then what's in those
responses is often the feature Flags the
the the Privileges the roles of your
account your username your user ID and
so doing Master place on those can be
super beneficial you can either do it in
intercept you know at runtime just to
like kind of mess with like a single
thing like let's say you wanted to see
if what what happened like what all
request does it make for IDs and can I
load Justin's ID just I'll go into
intercept and change it real quick once
right but if you're actually trying to
um view all the features in the app
maybe you do like a true to false but
it'll be like is admin equals true or
false or it'll be like a list of roles
or features and you'll match or place
those for the ones you want which you
found in Recon when you went through the
JavaScript and then um you know
sometimes they actually I don't know if
you've noticed this Justin I bet some
people are missing this sometimes it'll
like they'll have negative based
features like it'll be like is you know
there'll be like a enabled for this
feature or disabled for the feature and
if you put both those in there you're
not going to see the feature you got to
be smart about it yeah you have to go
through each one and I think that's
where we could also use an AI component
of this too like here here's some
feature Flags turn them on correctly you
know like cuz because you see that all
the freaking time you know you know is
not disabled or something like that it's
really crazy what people write in these
applications yeah um so you can't just
do like you know uh flag double quote
colon double quote you know false or to
true it it won't it won't work you have
to individually read each one of them
for a lot of the cases out there and I
really liked what you said regarding um
the groups as well that is one of the
most common implementations that I see
for these feature Flags is like there
the API endpoint kicks back like a role
a list of it'll say developer yeah and
and and then deep in the code it'll say
okay if they have the developer role
show them this yes you know and um and
and so what you got to do in those
scenarios is you've got to either match
and replace the Javascript file to just
always if they have one function that
they always do I always like match and
replace that function just say you know
yeah just turn it on you know for this
specific role you know has role or
something like that just always said it
to True um uh but the other thing is you
you can do exactly what you said and
just like match and replace all of the
roles you can find in the JS files into
that array and then you're you're Off to
the Races um and I think that's
something I kind of talked about this a
little bit before in the past but it's
something you don't want to do too early
on in your in your process I think I
think it's something you want to do
after you're like moderately familiar
with the application and the reason for
that is because you want to be able to
Spot the Difference yep I find I have
this issue all the time I look at the
spa and I'm like oh yeah yeah I can
match replace this I set it up and then
I like oh but what's new what and so I'm
like trying to refresh and swap it back
and look and figure it out yeah yeah
that's that's huge is you know let
yourself get used to the application let
your hacker eyes be like okay that's
feature this feature that feature and
then when you turn on the match and
replace you'll be like wait a second
that feature wasn't there before that
option wasn't like that and then and
then that's where you drill down because
that's where the the competition is
going to be the least right and um you
know most users are not going to have
access to those features so they're
going to be like tested yeah yeah that's
a great point and um as an aside there
uh this is like also a great way to test
for like whenever there are like not
only PR privilege escalation but also
like uh free features which I know is
not always the most impactful thing but
a lot of times if you match your place
for like a higher subscription level um
like you know a business or Pro
subscription and then you're able to use
some of those uh features or
functionality uh if the API calls work
under the hood with it yeah actually
yeah we should clarify this we have a
lot of newb listeners too not all of our
listeners are like super op just because
you can match your place and see more
features in single page apps is not a
vulnerability I'm sure a million people
have fallen for this I've fallen for
this just because it like looks
different and it says that you're an
admin if the API calls are 403 you know
if they're showing forbidden if you if
you aren't getting more actual real
functionality that affects other users
or that finds more vulnerabilities it's
not a bug so that's worth clarifying A
come on Joseph our boys know that you
know I'm sure I'm sure 90% of listeners
know maybe but there there are new
people who listen for that 10% there you
go yeah um all right yeah the the other
thing that I was going to shout out here
is um something that we covered recently
in the uh Dev tools master class that we
did in the in the critical thinkers
Discord um is that recorded are they
able to go back and listen if they sign
up it's up yeah it's up in there we we
did get it uploaded um but uh one of the
the things with that was with regards to
webpack files you know it's really nice
when you are looking at application and
the webpack map files are there and you
can just kind of be like okay you know
now I'm clicking through the actual like
source code and looking at typescript
rather than all this minified garbage
right um uh and sometimes these map
files are there but they're not linked
to the JS files so whenever you see
these J JS files loaded up and actually
this would be a great thing for somebody
to embed into an extension is um just
try that same JS file map yep and if it
does work then you can match and replace
that that or do a local override or
whatever that map file into place and
force the browser to to um you know
unpack the the web pack and now you've
got a beautiful you know breakout of JS
files and you're reading typescript
rather than minified garbage does the
browser look at the last line of the
file to know it does yeah so if you
that's where I always see it I but I
didn't know that was actual spec for how
it worked yeah that's that's the
Assumption I've made so yeah I think
that that is the the origin for it um
okay and it's worked in the past when
I've done it so cool um yeah so that's
great idea that's pretty pretty sick one
um I wanted to just mention I know you
probably mentioned it on the podcast 100
times but if anyone doesn't know about P
prettier that's definitely the best um
the best like command line tool and just
best tool in general for um cleaning up
uh prettified or um sorry minified
JavaScript yeah it dude and it's crazy
like if you search PR prettier like it
will not come up does it still not come
up yeah yeah so I'm search PR prettier
mixer or uh or or uh PR prettier or
parallel prettier is is actually I think
what it got renamed to after uh mixer
like gave it to Microsoft um but yeah
dude I mean it's performant it's it's uh
multi-threaded so it will like it will
very very quickly beautify these these
files um definitely the best one to use
out there definitely underrated let me
let me actually hold on let me grab that
link and I'll just drop I dropped it in
there did you okay yeah you're the man
you're the man all right um so what what
do we not want to do with an SP
application um brute forcing on the main
domain is not going to give you anything
anywhere it's likely just a an S3 bucket
um that should be pretty clear you're
going to be getting essentially Wild
Card responses to uh you know some S3
bucket if you try to hit a random path
um so that's definitely definitely not
what you're looking for typically these
apps are built off of a static HTML
front end on the S3 bucket and then an
API on the back end so you may want to
spend time you know brute forcing on
that API or attacking that API but to be
honest brute forcing apis is a little
bit tricky because the whole premise of
like traditional brute forcing is you
manipulate the fact that if you hit a
certain path that folder does exist you
see a 301 to to that name and then a
slash most of the time sure um and that
allows you to know that you've hit a a
folder that that's that's correct um and
you're not going to find that on API so
typically you know when you're attacking
these apis you want to be using
something a little bit more uh complex
like kite Rider um from the asset note
team um I have had mixed experiences
with Kite Runner um definitely the
concept is great and it's there and I
think it's one of those things that you
kind of just need to Deep dive and
understand how it works and to be
perfectly honest I haven't done that yet
um but the concept of doing a little bit
more smart a little bit more intelligent
a little bit more um oriented towards
API based brute forcing is essential if
you actually want to go the full
distance on these um on these apis yeah
they're not it's not overly fruitful but
I definitely have found some stuff with
just um if there there are sometimes
JavaScript or sorry some API end points
that are not in the JavaScript um but
you definitely have to fuzz at the
existing or known path that like you're
already observing in the app so you have
to like be in the app be manually
hacking it you notice that all the
requests are to slash management API V1
I'll just fuzz right at that V1 I don't
do like any kind of like deep precursive
fuzzing because like you said it's
completely fruitless right but at that
path it's still worth doing some fuzzing
just because you know if users user user
ID if user SL whatever um just because
those exist doesn't mean there might not
be some hidden pth like SLG groups or
slash admin or whatever I'll still some
sometimes find that stuff so yeah yeah
absolutely and and I think this is a
good area for um just kind of using your
brain or maybe even using AI to like
look at these paths this would be a cool
one dude this is what shadow repeater
should do is like look at the paths look
look at okay you know there's a get here
there's a post here with this structure
let me guess other other paths right and
that would be so easy to implement too
because you could just all you have to
do is have the llm take a look at it and
then just don't send a body I mean
unless unless it's like a delete request
and it might to like delete your
resources or whatever but like don't
don't have it use that verb yeah yeah or
or just be like okay uh if I'm deleting
it like and it's a uu ID just rotate the
number by like one or something like
that and then if it's a 404 then it's
it'll 404 and if it's like an applic
level 404 like couldn't find this thing
that you want me to delete then you know
that there's actually some functionality
there MH that's that's pretty cool
that's calling that application Level
404 is like a really neat word I'm glad
you just picked that I've never thought
about that before but I see those and
I've never known what to call them and I
feel like that's like a useful sometimes
having a word for a gadget or a
functionality enables you to talk about
it with other people in a way where and
it's a way if if you don't have a name
for something I feel like it's hard to
hold in your in your mind so like when
you're showering and having shower
thoughts you don't think about it so an
application Level 404 an application
level 200 or whatever I like the
application Level status codes or you
know response codes is a concept that
you just brought up because now it's in
my head and I'm gonna like think about
it more yeah because it's like okay
there's like an HTTP server level 404
right where it's I don't know where to
Route this right you know but then
there's also a 44 like hey I couldn't
find something when I was looking
through the database you know sort of
situation which is very different those
are very different outcomes y That's
right um so yeah I think understanding
that is that sort of concept is really
is really essential um what else do we
have on apis uh that that I think one of
the things that fron does well here is
just like just uses that hacker brain
and says like okay all of these things
are structured in this specific way I I
think that there is an endpoint here and
just kind of guesses these end points
just from his brain um and yeah I think
that's very few people have that skill
but some people do and it's really
impressive yeah it's it's awesome and
and man it's like that if you can just
get good at that and it's hard it's a
hard thing to get good at because you
don't get a lot of feedback like yes
that could have been a good guess but
the end point just doesn't exist you
know like uh so I think it takes a lot
of experience and a lot of time messing
around with web apps um but definitely
worth trying when you're on one of those
Cash Cow applications right where you're
like if I find another API endpoint
there's going to be another three ey
doors there you know like know like and
so I think in those applications where
it's cash cow this going this extra
level of like API level group forcing
you know trying to just use your brain
to guess maybe even utilizing an llm
with the paths that are currently there
um can lend you a couple extra bounties
for sure yeah um you were mentioning
what other things do we know about for
single page apps um I think you you put
this in the doc but yeah you definitely
don't see I think just because they're
newer and it's like a newer architecture
you don't see as much simple xss so like
yeah I feel like you might see more like
angularjs or something like that like
kind of those um dbased Xs yeah theas
xss or or like kind of store xss or you
might be able to like submit something
in the back end that renders in a
different application later but in
general just like simple xss on the page
you don't see very often yeah because
you know the front end is all static and
those apis are not often returning HTML
content type right it's almost all Json
stuff yeah and so and so it becomes a
lot more of a Dom xss game uh but the
trade-off for that is if you get good at
exploting Dom xss in single page
applications by looking for your
traditional syns you know your your
window.location your uh you know inent
HTML your document. write actually
somebody um I think it was the pdf.js
one from before I was so impressed with
the function Constructor one I I love
that that's that's so fun um uh but if
you get you know familiar with trying to
hit those Dom xss based xsss then the
trade-off in the single page application
is almost all of them use authorization
bear based off yep which means that if
you do get an xss and get gain control
of local storage or session storage
you're golden you just you got at I was
actually going to bring up that as like
a way to know when something is
potentially more vulnerable if you see
these single Page Apps and they're not
using baroth they're using like just
cookies only then I feel like it's such
a ripe Target for SE Surf and
specifically what I would do is like you
know use shift or something else to
modify those Json API calls into URL
form encoded and a lot of them just work
by default if they haven't disabled it a
lot of the backends that are um that
people ride apis in these days will just
like support either either form and so
it'll just work that's a great tip or or
the other thing is also like sending
like uh text Json or like uh it's not
text just plain plain text sometimes
text Json think uh works I think but um
if you send just text plane with Json in
the body and it parses the the Json then
you're good I don't look for that much I
need to look for that more yeah that's
something that I built a kaido work slow
that just automatically just checks like
oh just swap that out and and will let
me know if if uh if it accepts that
which is cool yeah the other thing I was
going to say is I feel like when these
single page apps are using beo it's
often good to check for gadgets for
manipulating the um components of the of
the
JWT and um specifically I'm thinking
about like some of like Joe hash's
findings um you know where you can
generate it for another user or like
basically go look at how the JWT is
generated and may be possible to
generate for another user or play with
the JWT and see if you can do uh if you
can resign it with like no um no key and
those sort of things yeah yeah so JWT
level attacks yep great point but also
just like understanding what the JWT is
looking at as an authentication
mechanism so um breaking apart the JWT
saying okay there's a subject field but
there's also an email field like I
wonder if it is using my subject field
or my email field you know as
authentication here and try to trying to
to piece that apart change youra and
then don't confirm it and then try to
make some calls right and stuff like
that oh dude that's such a good
idea reso dude yes that's a great idea
yeah that's a great simple attack that
you can pull off in so many apps I was
just thinking here I mean it doesn't
land you Bounty but it does probably let
you understand what is happening with
regards to what which one it's using
dude what item it's using brilliant okay
thank you thank you I need to when you
start looking for that a lot of places
right that's great now it's just helpful
because you know if you if you do know
that the app is is choosing something
like email as the the delimiter for for
what is um the auth authentication piece
of information then it becomes a lot
more doable to to trick it um if you
have any control of the JWT yeah and
that could be a small Gadget to control
that component of the
JWT to totally different topic but one
of my favorite vulnerabilities that I've
ever found to this day is inting into a
JWT like off bear that was semicolon Del
limited and uh you know I had control
over one of the fields and I was able to
inject a semicolon and then add other
fields into that off
bear it's the best man so it wasn't a
JWT but it was like like it it was like
roll your around yeah it was it was B 64
encoded um and it was semicolon
delimited yeah uh and so if you could
you know if you could just put in a
semicolon you could create a new field
you know it' be value equals key
semicolon right it was almost like um
like xww form encoded um sort of format
in there uh and I was able to break out
of those and add duplicate entries which
overrode the off mechanisms on certain
end points I don't know if there a
single page app specific maybe you tell
me if it is or isn't but I feel like um
something to check for just in general
is whether or not the the apps like that
especially some older apps are using so
probably not single page but are using
certain cookie values that are not off
related for determining either things to
draw on the page or even for o when they
shouldn't be like I'm sure you've seen I
mean it's like a classic example most
everyone's probably seen like username
equals your name as like a cookie which
obviously you can just change your own
cookies and it uses that at some point
on the server side to determine o when
it really shouldn't yeah dude that's
that is some area that I haven't seen
hackers really
like like major in you know there there
are some hackers that are like you know
yeah I'm really good with apis you know
I know the Json in andout you know like
everybody's kind of got thing maybe JWT
right could be somebody's um but I
haven't seen a really amazing web hacker
that's like yeah cookies are my [__]
like I know everything about every
single cookie in this application and I
think um there's some really good
opportunities for the the um HP proxy
plugins to to do something really cool
here where you can add notes for a
specific cookie on a specific uh domain
right so you can say okay you know this
cookie is cloud cookie you know and this
cookie is uh you know used for off in
this scenario or that scenario right and
then just filter these cookies out when
you're doing request and say okay you
know this one this one this one this
one's gone and then have something that
automatically reissues the request maybe
nonstate changing request or whatever it
says okay well you know this cookie and
this cookie and this cookie isn't
necessary in this request but one of
those is necessary in this other request
right weird yeah that's two different
systems right like there's two different
secondary contexts there and so now you
can kind of you know start to figure
that out out that's cool yeah or just
like you said the application logic is
saying oh I'm going to just use this
shortcut because this cookie is always
there as like a relic of the off
mechanism or something like that and I'm
going to rely on that as a as a a piece
of authentication information or or you
know application Level information where
you're accessing user data even though
that's not a an an author related cookie
yeah I mean someone should do that right
I mean people who become an expert in a
specific thing whether it's Chapman with
headless browsers or whether it's you
know people ranging me AI bugs or I know
that like would always reach out to hx1
with ooth bugs um I'm sure people reach
out to you for client side stuff if
somebody wants to be the to be the
Cookie Monster they can uh they can uh
figure that out dude I just we just
popped a um man me and and one of the
the members of the critical thinking
Community just popped like a super sick
bug um I'm going to talk about it in the
uh the full-time Hunters Guild meet and
greet later today um but I I I hope I'm
going to talk to him and and see you
know hey can we present it on the Pod
sometime because it's so simple you know
and the functionality is so the
functionality that this xss had was like
oh my God please let like this has to be
vulnerable like but it was just very AG
aggravatingly not vulnerable in like the
three or four ways that you would think
that oh I could just exploit it like
this and then finally there's like a
workaround at the end that we came which
is just like that's sick you love it
um okay uh so two things here uh cashing
attacks and then client side path
numeration so um let me let me talk for
a second about caching attacks um
caching attacks definitely do happen in
both U traditional applications and
single page applications but uh my
experience has been that it is a little
bit harder to get these caching based
attacks on single page applications
because uh they the user level logic is
sort of segmented out into these apis
and these apis probably don't have any
caching on them right um that's fair and
and so uh I I spend a little bit less
time looking for caching related issues
on these apis that being said uh I think
the vulnerability um so let me say this
when there isn't a different API host
right and there's there's just like a SL
API that is being rerouted away from the
S3 bucket or whatever for the single
page application and being routed to a
backend API then you're serving static
assets and API assets on the same host
there you go and that is where you start
seeing that those cash I love that's
such a great tip like if you see that
start looking deeper those little um
what are those called it's like whenever
um obviously we you know we say like
develop your sniffer and that sort of
thing but um man there's a word for that
that I can't think of but anyway like
like it's like an indicator that you an
indicator there you go it's an indicator
yeah that that there could be something
interesting here it's a trigger for you
to sort of investigate more yeah and
that's that's kind of what I meant by we
just need a word for that cuz we're
going to use it on the Pod all the time
speaking of it hit me earlier we need
the audience to help us come with a come
up with an Acme Corp name to use when
we're talking about bugs for companies
that we can't disclose right oh my gosh
yeah that's we need to come up with this
right this is actually on our to-do we
need to okay let me ask you this do you
think we should it is on R Todo but what
I what I told Richard our producer is
you know what we want to do is we want
to use a consistent name y uh for a
given Target so so we can talk about it
multiple Anonymous targets and not
complete the two okay right so we got to
come up like I think when Yugi
recommended was like George Foreman
grill or something like you know like
and just have some like over dramatized
voice instead of just bleep everything's
bleep right you know um but yeah so if
you have any recommendations chat drop
them in the uh the Pod talk Channel um
on Discord and we'll uh we'll we'll take
a look at those when we're trying to
bleep out things in the future yeah but
to Circle back so when I was saying
earlier if you see an like a an API
that's using cookie based o you should
look for URL form encoded or text Json
instead of the regular application Json
content type right so that's like
indicator and then thing to check for
and so like you're talking about that
with indicator and thing to check for so
if someone has a specific word for that
also reach out to us or do you think of
one right now Justin I would love like a
word for like that's your key to look
for something else yeah it's like a
trigger but the the the um analogy that
I used in my Defcon 2020 or um ncon 2020
talk where I was talking about source
code review was smelling blood you know
when when you see that you're like
something something's funky there let me
let me go check that out you know like
um and so I think that is a good way to
think about it is you should have these
triggers or these you you should be
smelling something funky you know when
you see these um various pieces of
functionality yeah perfect so any yeah
go on so I think you were mostly talking
about how with the when the API points
are shared did you did you have more to
say there yeah so um API end points
definitely um but one of the going back
to the apis um there was another one
that I wanted to highlight here which is
sometimes with these single page
applications you can swap out the API
backend and you can just sometimes it's
as simple as like naming your page Dev
or something like that window. name is
now Dev you know or something like that
and it will um trigger the backend to
switch to a different uh back API and
then you know there's lots of attacks
that that actually can be triggered from
that environment you can um one of the
ones that Sam herb uh does well and and
has exploited many times is the the
token swap um and you just you go to
that that um staging environment you
generate a JWT or session token it's
using the same signing secret so you put
it in the main application and even if
it's like user ID equals you know
256 then now your you whoever you user
ID 256 is in the main application W I
need to look for that so much more
that's genius yeah yeah so so that's
that's something that you can definitely
go after there um but swapping out the
IPI backend can not only do that but
also give you access to staging features
that aren't released on prod yet and um
I've had a good hit rate with reporting
um vulnerabilities in staging features
before they get to prod and saying like
hey might might want to fix this before
prod and even if staging isn't in scope
that typically gets accepted because it
was going to it would have been in soon
right yeah I think that um that also is
just like something that's kind of cool
about being a hacker it's like when you
see a single page app and you can see
like oh if it's you know Dev it's in
it's on Local Host if it's on staging
it's on this host if it's on this it's
on this host so it can also give you an
indicator of like their naming schemes
for things like they're naming schemes
for subdomains and stuff too so it's
like a kind of a nice little Recon
technique to go look and find you know
staging domains when you're looking at
single page apps yeah absolutely okay um
two more things here one that I can't
believe we pushed until the very end um
which is client side paths this is such
an a essential part of attacking single
page applications and I feel like a lot
of hackers that I know that are really
talented even ones that are quite good
at client side um don't understand this
concept of like client side paths and
server side paths so in a single page
application based
architecture um your path doesn't really
matter most of the time in the browser
it's going to be a static 200 that
they're going to be sending back that
says okay here's the single page
application here you go what does happen
though is that in the uh JavaScript code
they are utilizing the path and the you
know the state sometimes it's in in the
hash sometimes it's in the actual path
itself to determine what page you're on
in the application and show you
different parts of the UI um dynamically
without refreshing the page right
without causing a bunch of dead with
yeah I'm gonna sound like a super Noob
here so I'm a single page app I click
Like a new tab and in the URL bar I get
a slash to that tab name
MH I often won't get a request I guess
right right because it what's actually
what's what's happening there is when
you click that you know Navar link or
whatever yeah it's just simulating that
you're navigating right it's just
pushing it's using history. push State
typically I think um to change the path
name in the URL um I want to say it's
push date I have to double check on that
but um it's changing the path in the URL
without issuing another request right um
and and with that it's then it's going
to go into a client side router and that
router you have access to it's in the
code and one of the things I always
search for with client side applications
is I search for um excuse me single page
applications is uh path colon because
almost all of the um uh client side uh
environments Define the routers that way
so you do path colon and then a double
quote and then it'll say like okay SL
users SL Star right and when you see
that star you know okay that's an ID
there right and and um and then you you
can kind of build out these pieces of
client side uh functionality and this is
how you land C- surfs in these
applications is or or or CLI side path
rals is you say okay wow there's a um
client side endpoint called like uh call
back after verification you know to
change my email or whatever right you
sometimes it's really long like that too
on the callbacks and um you can just
force a user to hit that endpoint
directly and it doesn't expect that
you're navigating directly to that
endpoint and it will cause the C serves
um does that make sense sort of or yeah
no it's cool okay solid yeah so
enumerating those CLI side paths um
really big and then obviously that's
also where um CLI patch veral comes in
right where a piece of that URL is being
parged through your query parameter and
then it is then getting embedded in the
into a fetch request on the back end in
the path portion you can path Traverse
you can trunk it with a hashtag or a
query um question mark um and that's
sort of how we landed on this amazing uh
technique called client side path veral
um sorry I think the the place you were
going was that there are paths that are
parse both client side and server side
yeah exactly so you know you find those
paths you enumerate the functionality
sometimes you can H uh trigger Cerf
sometimes you can trigger cspt but at
the very least you understand all of the
attack surface you're dealing with in a
client side application and you know all
of the pages and if you see a page that
you haven't been to or you don't know
how to navigate to with the UI it's
something that you can s sort of make
sure that you're getting full coverage
on this client side application because
we have access to all the routes which
is awesome right yeah yeah sweet so
that's interesting so a lot of times I
will go pull all the paths and then I'll
kind of like fuzz for them but that's
also kind of silly to do sometimes yeah
I mean I you don't fuzz really in the in
the I mean you can you know manually put
them in your browser but you're not
you're not going to get any response
back if you hit it hit with like fuff or
something right yeah so that's
interesting do you have any way that you
like to like let's say it's a pretty
large Spa do you have anything that like
outputs you a list of links that you you
just like click them all in order to go
to all the pages to see if there's any
that you went to directly that you
couldn't find in the app yeah I mean
what I typically do is I'll I'll justum
dump all the JS beautify it GP for all
those endpoints and then just sub in the
IDS so often times I'll have like you
know there'll be a placeholder like user
ID or whatever well I just say user ID
is my user ID right and then it like
populates it and across all of those
plugins and then I just manually you
know one by one go through them because
you can't throw it into automate or or
um Intruder or anything because it's
like um it's not a a serers side thing
so you just manually got to put them in
the browser and you either you know
click to open them or you just you know
typically I don't like to open them all
at once because sometimes they'll
redirect and stuff happens so I T
typically one by one click and see what
happens trace the code you know and
that's how you really become intimate
that's how you get intimate with the
application you know um and that's what
we talk about here on the Pod is is how
important it is to be very in in with
the application and you can do that by
looking at these client side paths
enumerating each one and then one by one
going through and trying to exploit
functionality associated with each yep
sweet yeah okay dude um we're coming up
on time we're going to call it a wrap
here let me just shoot this last um this
last tip out there um obviously client
side applications um or single page
applications uh JavaScript files are
super important um luckily Wayback URLs
uh caches JS files so uh if you're
really really really really to do your
due diligence um you can uh hit those
way back URLs see see what kind of I
mean the client side paths are going to
be gone right but see what kind of API
endpoints were still in those um and see
what functionality used to be there and
where they might have integrated it
somewhere else um and with that diff it
can inform you more on on how to attack
the application yep yeah um I guess
maybe they tune in next week to see if
they uh will hear more browser based
scam tactics no brows R oh please Joseph
all right whatever that's the PO thanks
guys and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
watching to the end y'all if you want
more critical thinking content uh or if
you want to support the show head over
to ctbb doow Discord you can hop in the
community there's lots of great
highlevel hacking discussion happening
there on top of master classes hack
alongs exclusive content and a full-time
Hunter Guild if you're a full-time
Hunter it's a great time trust me all
right I'll see you there
oh